Matthew Malane

Profile

I'm a full-stack Software Engineer based in Orange County, California. I have a couple years experience in JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems and most recently built Nexus, an open source tool that generates a GraphQL API and deploys it to AWS.

Experience

Software Engineer & Co-Creator,

2022

Nexus, https://nexus-graphql.github.io/ ☐

An open-source tool that generates a GraphQL API from multiple data sources and deploys to AWS cloud infrastructure, abstracting away dozens of manual steps for fast setup.

- Led the development of a command line interface to automate GraphQL server generation, drastically reducing manual configuration (Node.js, Inquirer, Commander)
- Created a dashboard for API customization, testing, and deployment monitoring with a re-deployment notification system, hot-reloading local test server, and advanced data source configuration via GUI (React, Express, TailwindCSS)
- Resolved multi-source over-fetching and N+1 performance issues with dynamically generated custom GraphQL schema extensions and resolvers (GraphQL Mesh, YAML)
- Containerized server code for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure and automated AWS deployment and teardown (Docker, AWS CLI, Terraform, ECR, ECS Fargate)
- Authored technical case study and led a presentation about the application to a group of 50+ attendees. Read the case study and watch the presentation: nexus-graphql.github.io ☑

Software Engineer, additional open source projects

2020 - 2022

Selection of projects built during my two year career transition.

- RequestCloud A web application for receiving and debugging webhooks. (Node.js/Express, React, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Digital Ocean Droplet)
- Airline Routes Interactive Map for viewing and filtering airline routes. (React)
- TodoTrack Todolist tracker (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, ERB, Heroku)

Groundman, International Line Builders

2019 – 2020

Routine maintenance of power lines, emergency restoration work, and the rebuilding of an electrical grid.

EMT-Basic, Care Ambulance

2016 – 2018

EMT/ambulance driver across Los Angeles and Orange County in a 911 system.

Skills

BackendFrontendOtherNode.js, Express, Ruby, Golang,JavaScript, React, HTML,Git, GitHub, Docker,SQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, SinatraCSS, jQuery, HandlebarsTerraform, DigitalOcean (VPS),AWS (EC2, Fargate, ECS, ECR)

Education

Launch School, Software Engineering & Full-Stack Web Development

2020 - 2022

Mastery based education program focused on the fundamentals of software engineering.